

muchahigakinya@gmail.com

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a self driven professional individual with experience in crop science, agribusiness, agroforestry, tea/coffee growing and production. I am highly adaptable to a challenging environment, working with the available resources targeting to achieve the company's goals.

#### **EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND**

- Bachelor of Agriculture, crop science option KENYATTA UNIVERSITY. May 2013 up to June 2018 Second class honors, upper division.
- Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education, K.C.S.E,
  NJONJO GIRLS HIGH SCHOOL, NYAHURURU. Mean grade: B of 66 points. February 2009 to November 2012
- Kenya Certificate of Primary Education,
  LIONS PRIMARY GROUP OF SCHOOLS, 384 out of 500. 2001-2008

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# ZHURI MEDICARE HOSPITAL 12/2020 to Currently Duties and Responsibilities

- Customer care and service to the patients
- Accurate billing of patients
- Marketing of the institution.
- Keeping an open line of communication between patients and doctors/hospital staff.
- Doubled up as a cashier in the hospital.

#### Curriculum vitae

# SAFFRAN JAPAN GLOBAL EXPORTER 11/2018 to 07/2019

#### **Duties and Responsibilities:**

- Sales and Marketing of Saffron Products; cars for imports
- Accurate billing and processing of client's payments.
- Provide customer service to the company's clients.
- Training of new staff on the company's policies especially those assigned to me.
- Managing my team of three sales executives.
- Communication and developing good relationship rapport with potential clients
- Clearing of cars through a clearing agent company.

# SBT JAPAN GLOBAL EXPORTER 01/2018 to 10/2018

#### **Duties and Responsibilities:**

- Sales and Marketing of SBT JAPAN Products; cars for imports.
- Provide customer service to the company's clients.
- Accurate billing and processing of client's payments.
- Training of new staff on the company's policies especially those assigned to me.
- Managing my team of five sales executives.
- Communication and developing good relationship rapport with potential clients
- Clearing of cars through a clearing agent company.

#### **URBAN EATERY**

#### 05/2017 to 12/2017

### **Duties and Responsibilities:**

- Worked as a cashier in the restaurant.
- Provide customer service to the clients.
- Responsible for receiving and managing money from sales.
- Responsible for billing of clients.
- Keeping an open line of communication with the accountant
- Solving financial problems in case of mishaps.

#### **ATTACHMENT**

#### CIMMYT KALRO KIBOKO SUB CENTER, MAKUENI.

#### **Duties and responsibilities;**

- Planning, preparing and organizing of the casual's schedule at the farm.
- Developing research trials to be carried out in the farm.
- Monitoring, evaluating and recording casuals' progress and their duties.

- Providing guidance and instructions to the casuals on the farm as well as consulting with my supervisor.
- Handling work on seed preparation for setting up trials, field layouts and data collection on different trials located on the farm.
- Gained knowledge on nursery management and seed production

#### **COMPLETED AT REAL IPM THIKA**

#### **Duties and Responsibilities:**

- Planning, preparing and organizing of the casuals' schedule at the farm.
- Developing research trials to be carried out in the farm.
- Monitoring, evaluating and recording casuals' progress and their duties.
- Providing guidance and instructions to the casuals on the farm as well as consulting with my supervisor.
- Handling work on seed preparation for setting up trials, field layouts and data collection on different trials located on the farm.
- Gained knowledge on nursery management and seed production.

#### **OBJECTIVES**

- To work in a challenging environment.
- To achieve success both personally and professionally.
- To work in a fast class organization in order to sharpen my skills,
- To build relationships and connections for future reference.

#### PROFESSIONAL TRAINING, SEMINARS AND OTHER SHORT COURSES

- International Computer Driving License ICDL, Computer pride, Kenyatta Avenue- June 1, 2014 to August 29, 2014.
- Certificate in Computer application packages Nakuru Institute of Management Studies-December 2012 to January 2013.
- Certificates in community service and voluntary work.
- Certificate in ultimate customer service and telephone etiquette training.

#### KEY SKILLS AND COMPETENCIES

- Excellent customer service as well as good administrative skills including pleasant telephone mannerisms.
- I am a fast learner and able to retain information at first hear.
- I work well under work pressure.
- I have the ability to solve complex problems while being in a calm state or in busy environment.
- Ability to build good relationships as I am a team player.
- I possess good organizational and planning skills.
- Ability to collect, organize, analyze and interpret numerical data.
- I am open to new ideas and I am quick to adapt.

## INTERESTS AND HOBBIES

- Reading and staying abreast of current issues.
- Exploring and networking.
- Community service.
- Swimming

## **REFEREES**

NAME	COMPANY/ INSTITUTION	JOB TITLE	PHONE NUMBER
DR. JOSEPH GWEYI	KENYATTA UNIVERSITY	LECTURER	0714795463
MS.BECKY ONYANGO	SAFFRAN GLOBAL EXPORTER	GENERAL MANAGER	0724404102
MR. NADEEM ALIBHAI	SBT JAPAN	GENERAL MANAGER	0709915111

Curriculum vitae LEAH MUCHAHI GAKINYA

Curriculum vitae LEAH MUCHAHI GAKINYA